Infiltrate hate.
BlacKkKlansman is a crime, comedy, drama film directed by Spike Lee.
Colorado Springs, late 1970s.
Ron Stallworth, an African American police officer, and Flip Zimmerman, his Jewish
colleague, run an undercover operation to infiltrate the Ku Klux Klan.
Ron Stallworth, played by John David Washington.
Flip Zimmerman, played by Adam Driver.
David Duke, played by Topher Grace.
Patrice Dumas, played by Laura Harrier.
Dr. Kennebrew Beauregard, played by Alec Baldwin.
Felix Kendrickson, played by Jasper Pääkkönen.
BlacKkKlansman is a 2018 American biographical crime comedy-drama film directed by Spike Lee and written by Charlie Wachtel,
David Rabinowitz, Kevin Willmott and Lee, loosely based on the 2014 memoir Black Klansman by Ron Stallworth.
The film stars John David Washington as Stallworth, along with
Adam Driver, Laura Harrier, and Topher Grace.
It also features Harry Belafonte's last
performance before his death in April 2023.
Set in the 1970s in Colorado Springs, Colorado, it follows the first African-American detective in the
city's police department as he sets out to infiltrate and expose the local Ku Klux Klan chapter.
The film was produced by Lee, Raymond Mansfield, Shaun Redick,
Sean McKittrick, Jason Blum, and Jordan Peele.
It was packaged by Andy Frances, Stallworth's manager.
QC Entertainment purchased the film rights to the book in 2015.
Lee signed on as director in September 2017.
Much of the cast joined the following month, and
filming began in New York State.
BlacKkKlansman premiered on May 14, 2018, at the Cannes
Film Festival, where it won the Grand Prix.
It was theatrically released in the United States on August 10, 2018, a day before the
first anniversary of the Unite the Right rally in Charlottesville, Virginia.
The film received critical acclaim, with praise for Lee's direction, the
performances (particularly of Washington and Driver), and timely themes.
Critics  noted it as a return to form for Lee.
It received six nominations at the 91st Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best
Director (Lee's first directing nomination), and Best Supporting Actor for Driver.
It won for Best Adapted Screenplay, Lee's first competitive Academy Award.
The American Film Institute also selected it as one of the top 10 films of 2018.
At the 76th Golden Globe Awards, it earned four
nominations, including Best Motion Picture – Drama.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, ku klux
klan, 1970s, black panther party, biography.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.